<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>go-lang on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/tags/go-lang/</link><description>Recent content in go-lang on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 22:18:07 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AceTheOps.com/tags/go-lang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Functional programming in Go for beginners: A tutorial 👨🏼‍💻</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/functional-programming-golang/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/functional-programming-golang/</guid><description>Functional programming is a programming paradigm that emphasizes the use of functions to transform data and minimize the use of shared state and mutable data. In Go (also known as Golang), functional programming can be achieved using first-class functions, anonymous functions, and higher-order functions.
Golang is a multi-paradigm programming language. As a Golang programmer why uses functional programming? Golang is not a functional language but has a lot of features that enable us to applies functional principles in the development, turning our code more elegant, concise, maintainable, easier to understand and test.</description></item><item><title>Maximizing Performance with Concurrency in Go 👨🏼‍💻</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/concurrency-in-golang/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/concurrency-in-golang/</guid><description>Golang, or Go, is a programming language that is known for its simplicity, concurrency support, and efficient memory management. Concurrency in Go allows developers to write programs that can perform multiple tasks concurrently, allowing for faster and more efficient execution. In this blog post, we will explore the basics of concurrency in Go and provide some code examples to help you get started.
To begin, let&amp;rsquo;s define what we mean by concurrency.</description></item><item><title>Going deeper with Go sockets: Advanced concepts and techniques 🫡</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/golang-socket-programming-concepts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/golang-socket-programming-concepts/</guid><description>Welcome to this tutorial on advanced techniques for socket programming in Go! If you&amp;rsquo;re already familiar with the basics of socket programming in Go, or if you&amp;rsquo;ve completed one of our previous tutorials on the subject, you&amp;rsquo;re ready to take your skills to the next level.
In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore some advanced concepts and techniques for building more powerful and scalable networked applications using Go sockets. We&amp;rsquo;ll start with a brief overview of the socket API in Go, and then dive into a few specific areas where you can use sockets to build more advanced systems.</description></item><item><title>The Power of WhatsApp Automation: How Go Can Help you automating Whatsapp messaging 🫡</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/the-power-of-whatsapp-automation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/the-power-of-whatsapp-automation/</guid><description>WhatsApp is a popular messaging app that is used by millions of people around the world. In some cases, it may be useful to automate the process of sending messages through WhatsApp, for example, to send reminders or notifications to a large group of people.
One way to automate WhatsApp messaging is by using the Go programming language. Go is a popular language for building web applications and microservices, and it has a number of libraries and tools that make it easy to work with the WhatsApp API provided by Twilio.</description></item><item><title>Using GoLang and Elasticsearch to Crawl and Analyze Amazon.com Data 👨🏼‍💻</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/web-crawler-using-golang-and-elastic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/web-crawler-using-golang-and-elastic/</guid><description>Golang, or Go, is a programming language that is known for its simplicity, concurrency support, and efficient memory management. Concurrency in Go allows developers to write programs that can perform multiple tasks concurrently, allowing for faster and more efficient execution.
Crawling Amazon.com and storing the data in Elasticsearch using GoLang is a common use case for web crawlers. Elasticsearch is a popular search engine that can be used to store and search large amounts of data, making it an ideal choice for storing the results of a web crawl.</description></item><item><title>GoLang Frameworks: A Detailed Walkthrough of the Most Popular Options 🫵</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/famous-golang-frameworks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/famous-golang-frameworks/</guid><description>Go is a multiparadigm, statically-typed, and compiled programming language designed by Google. It is similar to C, and if you’re a fan of C, this can be an easy language to pick up. Many developers have embraced this language because of its garbage collection, memory safety, and structural typing system.
Why use Go? Before reviewing five top Go frameworks, what is Go truly used for? Aside from building general web applications, the language’s scope encompasses a wide range of use cases:</description></item><item><title>JWT Authentication using GoLang</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/jwt-authentication-using-golang/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 17:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/jwt-authentication-using-golang/</guid><description>What is JWT JSON Web Token (JWT) is a widely used standard for securely transmitting information between parties. It is commonly used to transmit information that can be verified and trusted, because it is digitally signed.
JWTs consist of three parts: a header, a payload, and a signature. The header typically consists of two parts: the type of the token, which is JWT, and the signing algorithm being used, such as HMAC SHA256 or RSA.</description></item></channel></rss>