<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>web on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</title><link>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/tags/web/</link><description>Recent content in web on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:18:07 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/tags/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Going deeper with Go sockets: Advanced concepts and techniques 🫡</title><link>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/golang-socket-programming-concepts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/golang-socket-programming-concepts/</guid><description>Welcome to this tutorial on advanced techniques for socket programming in Go! If you&amp;rsquo;re already familiar with the basics of socket programming in Go, or if you&amp;rsquo;ve completed one of our previous tutorials on the subject, you&amp;rsquo;re ready to take your skills to the next level.
In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore some advanced concepts and techniques for building more powerful and scalable networked applications using Go sockets. We&amp;rsquo;ll start with a brief overview of the socket API in Go, and then dive into a few specific areas where you can use sockets to build more advanced systems.</description></item><item><title>GoLang Frameworks: A Detailed Walkthrough of the Most Popular Options 🫵</title><link>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/famous-golang-frameworks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/famous-golang-frameworks/</guid><description>Go is a multiparadigm, statically-typed, and compiled programming language designed by Google. It is similar to C, and if you’re a fan of C, this can be an easy language to pick up. Many developers have embraced this language because of its garbage collection, memory safety, and structural typing system.
Why use Go? Before reviewing five top Go frameworks, what is Go truly used for? Aside from building general web applications, the language’s scope encompasses a wide range of use cases:</description></item><item><title>JWT Authentication using GoLang</title><link>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/jwt-authentication-using-golang/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 17:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/jwt-authentication-using-golang/</guid><description>What is JWT JSON Web Token (JWT) is a widely used standard for securely transmitting information between parties. It is commonly used to transmit information that can be verified and trusted, because it is digitally signed.
JWTs consist of three parts: a header, a payload, and a signature. The header typically consists of two parts: the type of the token, which is JWT, and the signing algorithm being used, such as HMAC SHA256 or RSA.</description></item></channel></rss>