<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>best_practices on Ace The Cloud Skills</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/tags/best_practices/</link><description>Recent content in best_practices on Ace The Cloud Skills</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 22:18:07 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://preview.acethecloud.com/tags/best_practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Maximizing Performance with Concurrency in Go 👨🏼‍💻</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/concurrency-in-golang/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/concurrency-in-golang/</guid><description>Golang, or Go, is a programming language that is known for its simplicity, concurrency support, and efficient memory management. Concurrency in Go allows developers to write programs that can perform multiple tasks concurrently, allowing for faster and more efficient execution. In this blog post, we will explore the basics of concurrency in Go and provide some code examples to help you get started.
To begin, let&amp;rsquo;s define what we mean by concurrency.</description></item><item><title>Maximize your productivity as an SRE with these 100 Linux commands 💪</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/linux-commands-for-sre/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/linux-commands-for-sre/</guid><description>Site Reliability Engineer (SRE) is a role within an organization that is responsible for ensuring the reliability, performance, and uptime of the company&amp;rsquo;s systems and applications. SREs work closely with development teams to design, build, and maintain scalable and reliable systems, and use a combination of software engineering and operations skills to improve the reliability and performance of the company&amp;rsquo;s systems.
Here are some tips for debugging as an SRE Gather as much information as possible : Before starting to debug, try to gather as much information as possible about the problem.</description></item></channel></rss>