<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>devops on Ace The Cloud Skills</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/tags/devops/</link><description>Recent content in devops on Ace The Cloud Skills</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:38:27 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://preview.acethecloud.com/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Debugging in Azure Cloud: A Comprehensive Guide 🔍</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/debugging-in-azure-cloud/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/debugging-in-azure-cloud/</guid><description>As a cloud developer, it is inevitable that you will encounter bugs and issues in your production environment. Debugging these issues can be a daunting task, especially if you are not familiar with the tools and techniques available in Azure Cloud. In this article, we will provide a comprehensive guide to debugging in Azure Cloud, including best practices, tools, and code examples. 💻
Before diving into debugging techniques, it is important to understand the different types of issues that can arise in a production environment.</description></item><item><title>Deploying microservices to Azure Kubernetes Service: A tutorial</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/azure-kubernetes-service/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/azure-kubernetes-service/</guid><description>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) is a managed Kubernetes service offered by Microsoft Azure. It enables users to quickly and easily deploy, manage, and scale containerized applications on Azure.
Kubernetes is an open-source container orchestration platform that allows developers to automate the deployment, scaling, and management of containerized applications. It uses a declarative configuration to define the desired state of an application and continuously works to maintain that state.
With AKS, users can leverage the power of Kubernetes without having to worry about the underlying infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Best practices for securing your Azure Kubernetes Service deployment</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/securing-azure-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/securing-azure-kubernetes/</guid><description>Securing your Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) deployment is crucial to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of your applications and data. In this blog post, we will explore some best practices for securing your AKS deployment.
1. Use Azure AD for authentication and authorization . Azure AD provides centralized identity and access management for your AKS cluster. You can use Azure AD to authenticate users and grant them access to the cluster and its resources.</description></item></channel></rss>