<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog on Ace The Cloud Skills</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/categories/blog/</link><description>Recent content in blog on Ace The Cloud Skills</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 22:18:07 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://preview.acethecloud.com/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Engineering Career Path: How to Advance Your Career in the Field</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/roadmap-for-data-engineering/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/roadmap-for-data-engineering/</guid><description>As a data engineer, you play a crucial role in helping organizations derive insights and make data-driven decisions. From building data pipelines to managing large datasets, the responsibilities of a data engineer are vast and varied. To succeed in this field, it&amp;rsquo;s important to have a solid foundation in the skills and technologies outlined in our data engineering roadmap.
But mastering data engineering goes beyond just learning the tools of the trade.</description></item><item><title>The Tech Behind the Metaverse: An Overview for Developers</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/metaverse-introduction/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/metaverse-introduction/</guid><description>A metaverse 🌌 is a virtual world 🌎 that is created by the collective imagination 🧠 of its users and can be accessed through the internet 🌐. It is a shared digital space 💻 where people 🙍‍♂️🙍‍♀️ can interact with each other 🤝 and with virtual objects 💎 and environments 🌲 in real-time.
Metaverses 🌌 have been around for decades, but recent advances in technology 🤖 have made it possible for developers 💻 to create more immersive and interactive experiences.</description></item><item><title>Debugging in Azure Cloud: A Comprehensive Guide 🔍</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/azure-cloud-debugging-production-issues/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/azure-cloud-debugging-production-issues/</guid><description>As a cloud developer, it is inevitable that you will encounter bugs and issues in your production environment. Debugging these issues can be a daunting task, especially if you are not familiar with the tools and techniques available in Azure Cloud. In this article, we will provide a comprehensive guide to debugging in Azure Cloud, including best practices, tools, and code examples. 💻
Before diving into debugging techniques, it is important to understand the different types of issues that can arise in a production environment.</description></item><item><title>Functional programming in Go for beginners: A tutorial 👨🏼‍💻</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/functional-programming-golang/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/functional-programming-golang/</guid><description>Functional programming is a programming paradigm that emphasizes the use of functions to transform data and minimize the use of shared state and mutable data. In Go (also known as Golang), functional programming can be achieved using first-class functions, anonymous functions, and higher-order functions.
Golang is a multi-paradigm programming language. As a Golang programmer why uses functional programming? Golang is not a functional language but has a lot of features that enable us to applies functional principles in the development, turning our code more elegant, concise, maintainable, easier to understand and test.</description></item><item><title>Maximizing Performance with Concurrency in Go 👨🏼‍💻</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/concurrency-in-golang/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/concurrency-in-golang/</guid><description>Golang, or Go, is a programming language that is known for its simplicity, concurrency support, and efficient memory management. Concurrency in Go allows developers to write programs that can perform multiple tasks concurrently, allowing for faster and more efficient execution. In this blog post, we will explore the basics of concurrency in Go and provide some code examples to help you get started.
To begin, let&amp;rsquo;s define what we mean by concurrency.</description></item><item><title>The Kubernetes Handbook: A Comprehensive guide of 100 Q&amp;A</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/kubernetes-handbook-100-qustions-answers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/kubernetes-handbook-100-qustions-answers/</guid><description>Here are 100 questions that could potentially be asked on a Kubernetes exam or as part of a technical interview: What is Kubernetes? What are the main components of a Kubernetes cluster? What is a pod in Kubernetes? What is a node in Kubernetes? What is a cluster in Kubernetes? What is the Kubernetes API used for? What is kubectl used for? What is a Deployment in Kubernetes? What is Helm used for?</description></item><item><title>Understanding a fair comparison between Cassandra MongoDB and MySQL 👨🏼‍💻</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/cassaandra-mongodb-mysql/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/cassaandra-mongodb-mysql/</guid><description>When choosing between Cassandra, MongoDB, and MySQL, it&amp;rsquo;s important to consider the specific requirements of your project and how each database management system (DBMS) meets those needs.
Here are some points to consider when deciding which DBMS to use:
➜ Data model : Cassandra and MongoDB are both NoSQL databases, which means they use a non-relational data model. This can be beneficial for handling large amounts of unstructured data, or for storing data with complex relationships.</description></item><item><title>Going deeper with Go sockets: Advanced concepts and techniques 🫡</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/golang-socket-programming-concepts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/golang-socket-programming-concepts/</guid><description>Welcome to this tutorial on advanced techniques for socket programming in Go! If you&amp;rsquo;re already familiar with the basics of socket programming in Go, or if you&amp;rsquo;ve completed one of our previous tutorials on the subject, you&amp;rsquo;re ready to take your skills to the next level.
In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore some advanced concepts and techniques for building more powerful and scalable networked applications using Go sockets. We&amp;rsquo;ll start with a brief overview of the socket API in Go, and then dive into a few specific areas where you can use sockets to build more advanced systems.</description></item><item><title>The Power of WhatsApp Automation: How Go Can Help you automating Whatsapp messaging 🫡</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/the-power-of-whatsapp-automation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/the-power-of-whatsapp-automation/</guid><description>WhatsApp is a popular messaging app that is used by millions of people around the world. In some cases, it may be useful to automate the process of sending messages through WhatsApp, for example, to send reminders or notifications to a large group of people.
One way to automate WhatsApp messaging is by using the Go programming language. Go is a popular language for building web applications and microservices, and it has a number of libraries and tools that make it easy to work with the WhatsApp API provided by Twilio.</description></item><item><title>Deploying microservices to Azure Kubernetes Service: A tutorial</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/azure-kubernetes-service/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/azure-kubernetes-service/</guid><description>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) is a managed Kubernetes service offered by Microsoft Azure. It enables users to quickly and easily deploy, manage, and scale containerized applications on Azure.
Kubernetes is an open-source container orchestration platform that allows developers to automate the deployment, scaling, and management of containerized applications. It uses a declarative configuration to define the desired state of an application and continuously works to maintain that state.
With AKS, users can leverage the power of Kubernetes without having to worry about the underlying infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Using GoLang and Elasticsearch to Crawl and Analyze Amazon.com Data 👨🏼‍💻</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/web-crawler-using-golang-and-elastic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/web-crawler-using-golang-and-elastic/</guid><description>Golang, or Go, is a programming language that is known for its simplicity, concurrency support, and efficient memory management. Concurrency in Go allows developers to write programs that can perform multiple tasks concurrently, allowing for faster and more efficient execution.
Crawling Amazon.com and storing the data in Elasticsearch using GoLang is a common use case for web crawlers. Elasticsearch is a popular search engine that can be used to store and search large amounts of data, making it an ideal choice for storing the results of a web crawl.</description></item><item><title>Building a scalable and reliable e-commerce platform with .NET and Azure 🫡</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/ecommerce-platform-with-dotnet-and-azure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/ecommerce-platform-with-dotnet-and-azure/</guid><description>E-commerce is an increasingly competitive and fast-paced industry, and building a scalable and reliable e-commerce platform is crucial for success. .NET and Azure offer a powerful combination of technologies for building such a platform, providing the tools you need to create a beautiful and intuitive shopping experience, store and manage product data, process payments, fulfill orders, and optimize performance.
In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to use .NET and Azure to build a scalable and reliable e-commerce platform, covering the following topics:</description></item><item><title>GoLang Frameworks: A Detailed Walkthrough of the Most Popular Options 🫵</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/famous-golang-frameworks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/famous-golang-frameworks/</guid><description>Go is a multiparadigm, statically-typed, and compiled programming language designed by Google. It is similar to C, and if you’re a fan of C, this can be an easy language to pick up. Many developers have embraced this language because of its garbage collection, memory safety, and structural typing system.
Why use Go? Before reviewing five top Go frameworks, what is Go truly used for? Aside from building general web applications, the language’s scope encompasses a wide range of use cases:</description></item><item><title>From Black Box to Glass Box: Using Explainable AI and Model Monitoring to Improve AI Performance and Transparency 💪🏻</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/explainable-ai/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 18:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/explainable-ai/</guid><description>Background Artificial intelligence (AI) has the potential to revolutionize many industries and transform the way we live and work. However, as AI systems become more complex and sophisticated, it can be challenging to understand how they are making decisions and why they are making those decisions. This lack of transparency can be a significant barrier to the adoption of AI, as it can make it difficult for organizations to trust and rely on these systems.</description></item><item><title>Best practices for securing your Azure Kubernetes Service deployment</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/securing-azure-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/securing-azure-kubernetes/</guid><description>Securing your Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) deployment is crucial to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of your applications and data. In this blog post, we will explore some best practices for securing your AKS deployment.
1. Use Azure AD for authentication and authorization . Azure AD provides centralized identity and access management for your AKS cluster. You can use Azure AD to authenticate users and grant them access to the cluster and its resources.</description></item><item><title>MLOPS 101: An Introduction to Managing Machine Learning in Production</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/introduction-to-mlops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/introduction-to-mlops/</guid><description>Background The practices and technology of Machine Learning Operations (MLOps) offer a managed, scalable means to deploy and monitor machine learning models within production environments. MLOps best practices allow businesses to successfully run AI.
MLOps is modeled on DevOps, the existing practice of more efficiently writing, deploying, and managing enterprise applications. DevOps began as a way to unite software developers (the Devs) and IT operations teams (the Ops), destroying data silos and enabling better collaboration.</description></item><item><title>A Beginner's Guide to Machine Learning Algorithms</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/machine-learning-algorithms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/machine-learning-algorithms/</guid><description>Machine learning algorithms are a set of techniques that allow computers to learn from data and make predictions or decisions without explicit programming. These algorithms can be broadly classified into three categories: supervised learning, unsupervised learning, and reinforcement learning.
Categories of Machine Learning Algorithms 1. Supervised learning algorithms: Supervised learning algorithms are used when we have a dataset with labeled input and output examples. The goal of these algorithms is to learn a function that can map the input data to the corresponding output labels.</description></item><item><title>A Beginner's Guide to Multi-Cloud Networking: Key Concepts and Best Practices</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/multicloud-networking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 20:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/multicloud-networking/</guid><description>Multi-cloud networking refers to the ability to connect and use multiple cloud computing environments, such as Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft Azure, and Google Cloud Platform (GCP), in a coordinated manner. This allows organizations to take advantage of the different features and capabilities offered by each cloud provider, and to create a more resilient and flexible infrastructure.
There are several ways to enable multi-cloud networking, depending on your specific requirements and the tools and services you are using.</description></item><item><title>Maximizing Cloud-Native Success with the Twelve-Factor App Methodology 🫡</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/twelve-factor-app/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 17:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/twelve-factor-app/</guid><description>Twelve Factor App Methodology The Twelve-Factor App methodology is a set of best practices for building and deploying cloud-native applications. It was developed by Heroku, a cloud platform as a service (PaaS) provider, and has since been widely adopted by organizations as a guide for building cloud-native applications.
The Twelve-Factor App methodology consists of 12 principles that are designed to help developers build applications that are easy to scale, maintain, and deploy in a cloud environment.</description></item><item><title>JWT Authentication using GoLang</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/jwt-authentication-using-golang/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 17:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/jwt-authentication-using-golang/</guid><description>What is JWT JSON Web Token (JWT) is a widely used standard for securely transmitting information between parties. It is commonly used to transmit information that can be verified and trusted, because it is digitally signed.
JWTs consist of three parts: a header, a payload, and a signature. The header typically consists of two parts: the type of the token, which is JWT, and the signing algorithm being used, such as HMAC SHA256 or RSA.</description></item><item><title>Azure Databricks for Enthusiasts: A Beginner's Guide</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/when-and-why-to-use-azure-databricks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/when-and-why-to-use-azure-databricks/</guid><description>Azure Data Bricks Azure Databricks is a powerful analytics platform that combines the best of Apache Spark and Azure cloud computing. It is a fully managed service that allows users to quickly and easily build, train, and deploy machine learning models, as well as explore and analyze large data sets.
So, when might Azure Databricks be a good choice for your organization? Here are a few key scenarios:
➼ Large-scale data processing and analysis: If you have large data sets that need to be processed and analyzed quickly, Azure Databricks can be a great solution.</description></item><item><title>Maximize your productivity as an SRE with these 100 Linux commands 💪</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/linux-commands-for-sre/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/linux-commands-for-sre/</guid><description>Site Reliability Engineer (SRE) is a role within an organization that is responsible for ensuring the reliability, performance, and uptime of the company&amp;rsquo;s systems and applications. SREs work closely with development teams to design, build, and maintain scalable and reliable systems, and use a combination of software engineering and operations skills to improve the reliability and performance of the company&amp;rsquo;s systems.
Here are some tips for debugging as an SRE Gather as much information as possible : Before starting to debug, try to gather as much information as possible about the problem.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Native vs Cloud Agnostic: Weighing the Trade-Offs 🤜 🤛</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/cloud-native-vs-cloud-agnostic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 20:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/cloud-native-vs-cloud-agnostic/</guid><description>Background Speed ​​is an important factor for business in this era when customers are looking for instant gratification. If the fact doesn&amp;rsquo;t convince you, the statistics might. An element as simple as a website&amp;rsquo;s load time carries weight. Statistics indicate that the first five seconds of a page load time have the greatest impact on conversion rates. So when consumer behavior has the greatest impact, it is profitable in the long run to modernize a business model accordingly.</description></item><item><title>Which Azure Messaging Service is Right for Your Use Case? A Comparison and Code Walkthrough 🤜 🤛</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/azure-messaging-options/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/azure-messaging-options/</guid><description>Azure offers a variety of messaging options to help developers build reliable, scalable, and high-performance applications. These options include:
Azure Service Bus : A fully managed messaging service that provides reliable message delivery and support for a variety of messaging patterns, including point-to-point, publish-subscribe, and request-response.
Azure Event Grid : A fully managed event routing service that enables developers to build reactive and event-driven applications. Event Grid supports a wide range of event sources and can deliver events to various destinations, including Azure Functions, Azure Logic Apps, and Azure Event Hubs.</description></item><item><title>Which is better Azure App Gateway or Nginx configured on Azure VMs 🤜 🤛</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/azure-application-gateway-and-nginx-on-vm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/azure-application-gateway-and-nginx-on-vm/</guid><description>Azure Application Gateway is a web traffic load balancer that enables you to manage traffic to your web applications. It includes features such as SSL/TLS offload, HTTP/HTTPS redirection, and cookie-based affinity.
Nginx is an open-source web server that can also be used as a reverse proxy, load balancer, and HTTP cache. When running Nginx on an Azure Virtual Machine (VM), you have the ability to customize the configuration and install additional modules to suit your needs.</description></item><item><title>Why Your Organization Needs a Service Mesh: The Benefits of Service Mesh Architecture and Istio</title><link>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/service-mesh-and-istio/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 20:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://preview.acethecloud.com/blog/service-mesh-and-istio/</guid><description>Background A lot has changed about how we built microservices, and most people have no choice but to deploy microservices as pods in Kubernetes. Let us take an example where we are running a web application that queries data for the products. If both of these functionalities were on the webserver, then a calculation could slow the response time of the web pages. Having it on a seperate server avoids this problem.</description></item></channel></rss>