<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ml on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/tags/ml/</link><description>Recent content in ml on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 18:18:07 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AceTheOps.com/tags/ml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>From Black Box to Glass Box: Using Explainable AI and Model Monitoring to Improve AI Performance and Transparency 💪🏻</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/explainable-ai/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 18:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/explainable-ai/</guid><description>Background Artificial intelligence (AI) has the potential to revolutionize many industries and transform the way we live and work. However, as AI systems become more complex and sophisticated, it can be challenging to understand how they are making decisions and why they are making those decisions. This lack of transparency can be a significant barrier to the adoption of AI, as it can make it difficult for organizations to trust and rely on these systems.</description></item><item><title>MLOPS 101: An Introduction to Managing Machine Learning in Production</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/introduction-to-mlops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/introduction-to-mlops/</guid><description>Background The practices and technology of Machine Learning Operations (MLOps) offer a managed, scalable means to deploy and monitor machine learning models within production environments. MLOps best practices allow businesses to successfully run AI.
MLOps is modeled on DevOps, the existing practice of more efficiently writing, deploying, and managing enterprise applications. DevOps began as a way to unite software developers (the Devs) and IT operations teams (the Ops), destroying data silos and enabling better collaboration.</description></item><item><title>A Beginner's Guide to Machine Learning Algorithms</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/machine-learning-algorithms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/machine-learning-algorithms/</guid><description>Machine learning algorithms are a set of techniques that allow computers to learn from data and make predictions or decisions without explicit programming. These algorithms can be broadly classified into three categories: supervised learning, unsupervised learning, and reinforcement learning.
Categories of Machine Learning Algorithms 1. Supervised learning algorithms: Supervised learning algorithms are used when we have a dataset with labeled input and output examples. The goal of these algorithms is to learn a function that can map the input data to the corresponding output labels.</description></item></channel></rss>