<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gcp on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/tags/gcp/</link><description>Recent content in Gcp on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 20:18:07 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AceTheOps.com/tags/gcp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Beginner's Guide to Multi-Cloud Networking: Key Concepts and Best Practices</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/multicloud-networking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 20:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/multicloud-networking/</guid><description>Multi-cloud networking refers to the ability to connect and use multiple cloud computing environments, such as Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft Azure, and Google Cloud Platform (GCP), in a coordinated manner. This allows organizations to take advantage of the different features and capabilities offered by each cloud provider, and to create a more resilient and flexible infrastructure.
There are several ways to enable multi-cloud networking, depending on your specific requirements and the tools and services you are using.</description></item><item><title>Maximizing Cloud-Native Success with the Twelve-Factor App Methodology 🫡</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/twelve-factor-app/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 17:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/twelve-factor-app/</guid><description>Twelve Factor App Methodology The Twelve-Factor App methodology is a set of best practices for building and deploying cloud-native applications. It was developed by Heroku, a cloud platform as a service (PaaS) provider, and has since been widely adopted by organizations as a guide for building cloud-native applications.
The Twelve-Factor App methodology consists of 12 principles that are designed to help developers build applications that are easy to scale, maintain, and deploy in a cloud environment.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Native vs Cloud Agnostic: Weighing the Trade-Offs 🤜 🤛</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/cloud-native-vs-cloud-agnostic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 20:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/cloud-native-vs-cloud-agnostic/</guid><description>Background Speed ​​is an important factor for business in this era when customers are looking for instant gratification. If the fact doesn&amp;rsquo;t convince you, the statistics might. An element as simple as a website&amp;rsquo;s load time carries weight. Statistics indicate that the first five seconds of a page load time have the greatest impact on conversion rates. So when consumer behavior has the greatest impact, it is profitable in the long run to modernize a business model accordingly.</description></item></channel></rss>