<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sre on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</title><link>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/tags/sre/</link><description>Recent content in sre on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:38:27 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/tags/sre/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Debugging in Azure Cloud: A Comprehensive Guide 🔍</title><link>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/azure-cloud-debugging-production-issues/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/azure-cloud-debugging-production-issues/</guid><description>As a cloud developer, it is inevitable that you will encounter bugs and issues in your production environment. Debugging these issues can be a daunting task, especially if you are not familiar with the tools and techniques available in Azure Cloud. In this article, we will provide a comprehensive guide to debugging in Azure Cloud, including best practices, tools, and code examples. 💻
Before diving into debugging techniques, it is important to understand the different types of issues that can arise in a production environment.</description></item><item><title>Maximize your productivity as an SRE with these 100 Linux commands 💪</title><link>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/linux-commands-for-sre/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/linux-commands-for-sre/</guid><description>Site Reliability Engineer (SRE) is a role within an organization that is responsible for ensuring the reliability, performance, and uptime of the company&amp;rsquo;s systems and applications. SREs work closely with development teams to design, build, and maintain scalable and reliable systems, and use a combination of software engineering and operations skills to improve the reliability and performance of the company&amp;rsquo;s systems.
Here are some tips for debugging as an SRE Gather as much information as possible : Before starting to debug, try to gather as much information as possible about the problem.</description></item></channel></rss>