<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud_Agnostic on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/tags/cloud_agnostic/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud_Agnostic on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:38:27 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AceTheOps.com/tags/cloud_agnostic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Kubernetes Handbook: A Comprehensive guide of 100 Q&amp;A</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/kubernetes-handbook-100-qustions-answers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/kubernetes-handbook-100-qustions-answers/</guid><description>Here are 100 questions that could potentially be asked on a Kubernetes exam or as part of a technical interview: What is Kubernetes? What are the main components of a Kubernetes cluster? What is a pod in Kubernetes? What is a node in Kubernetes? What is a cluster in Kubernetes? What is the Kubernetes API used for? What is kubectl used for? What is a Deployment in Kubernetes? What is Helm used for?</description></item><item><title>Cloud Native vs Cloud Agnostic: Weighing the Trade-Offs 🤜 🤛</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/cloud-native-vs-cloud-agnostic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 20:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/cloud-native-vs-cloud-agnostic/</guid><description>Background Speed ​​is an important factor for business in this era when customers are looking for instant gratification. If the fact doesn&amp;rsquo;t convince you, the statistics might. An element as simple as a website&amp;rsquo;s load time carries weight. Statistics indicate that the first five seconds of a page load time have the greatest impact on conversion rates. So when consumer behavior has the greatest impact, it is profitable in the long run to modernize a business model accordingly.</description></item></channel></rss>