<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>microservices on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</title><link>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/tags/microservices/</link><description>Recent content in microservices on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 22:18:07 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/tags/microservices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GoLang Frameworks: A Detailed Walkthrough of the Most Popular Options 🫵</title><link>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/famous-golang-frameworks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/famous-golang-frameworks/</guid><description>Go is a multiparadigm, statically-typed, and compiled programming language designed by Google. It is similar to C, and if you’re a fan of C, this can be an easy language to pick up. Many developers have embraced this language because of its garbage collection, memory safety, and structural typing system.
Why use Go? Before reviewing five top Go frameworks, what is Go truly used for? Aside from building general web applications, the language’s scope encompasses a wide range of use cases:</description></item><item><title>JWT Authentication using GoLang</title><link>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/jwt-authentication-using-golang/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 17:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/jwt-authentication-using-golang/</guid><description>What is JWT JSON Web Token (JWT) is a widely used standard for securely transmitting information between parties. It is commonly used to transmit information that can be verified and trusted, because it is digitally signed.
JWTs consist of three parts: a header, a payload, and a signature. The header typically consists of two parts: the type of the token, which is JWT, and the signing algorithm being used, such as HMAC SHA256 or RSA.</description></item></channel></rss>