<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>best-practices on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</title><link>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/tags/best-practices/</link><description>Recent content in best-practices on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 17:38:27 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/tags/best-practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Amabassador Pattern</title><link>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/amabassador-pattern/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 17:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/amabassador-pattern/</guid><description>Resilient cloud-based applications require features such as circuit breaking, routing, metering and monitoring, and the ability to make network-related configuration updates. It may be difficult or impossible to update legacy applications or existing code libraries to add these features, because the code is no longer maintained or can&amp;rsquo;t be easily modified by the development team.
Network calls also require substantial configuration for connection, authentication, and authorization. If these calls are used across multiple applications, built using multiple languages and frameworks, the calls must be configured for each of these instances.</description></item><item><title>Maximizing Cloud-Native Success with the Twelve-Factor App Methodology 🫡</title><link>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/twelve-factor-app/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 17:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/twelve-factor-app/</guid><description>Twelve Factor App Methodology The Twelve-Factor App methodology is a set of best practices for building and deploying cloud-native applications. It was developed by Heroku, a cloud platform as a service (PaaS) provider, and has since been widely adopted by organizations as a guide for building cloud-native applications.
The Twelve-Factor App methodology consists of 12 principles that are designed to help developers build applications that are easy to scale, maintain, and deploy in a cloud environment.</description></item></channel></rss>