<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>data on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</title><link>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/tags/data/</link><description>Recent content in data on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 22:18:07 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Engineering Career Path: How to Advance Your Career in the Field</title><link>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/roadmap-for-data-engineering/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/roadmap-for-data-engineering/</guid><description>As a data engineer, you play a crucial role in helping organizations derive insights and make data-driven decisions. From building data pipelines to managing large datasets, the responsibilities of a data engineer are vast and varied. To succeed in this field, it&amp;rsquo;s important to have a solid foundation in the skills and technologies outlined in our data engineering roadmap.
But mastering data engineering goes beyond just learning the tools of the trade.</description></item><item><title>Azure Databricks for Enthusiasts: A Beginner's Guide</title><link>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/when-and-why-to-use-azure-databricks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/when-and-why-to-use-azure-databricks/</guid><description>Azure Data Bricks Azure Databricks is a powerful analytics platform that combines the best of Apache Spark and Azure cloud computing. It is a fully managed service that allows users to quickly and easily build, train, and deploy machine learning models, as well as explore and analyze large data sets.
So, when might Azure Databricks be a good choice for your organization? Here are a few key scenarios:
➼ Large-scale data processing and analysis: If you have large data sets that need to be processed and analyzed quickly, Azure Databricks can be a great solution.</description></item></channel></rss>