<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>azure on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/tags/azure/</link><description>Recent content in azure on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:38:27 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AceTheOps.com/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Debugging in Azure Cloud: A Comprehensive Guide 🔍</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/azure-cloud-debugging-production-issues/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/azure-cloud-debugging-production-issues/</guid><description>As a cloud developer, it is inevitable that you will encounter bugs and issues in your production environment. Debugging these issues can be a daunting task, especially if you are not familiar with the tools and techniques available in Azure Cloud. In this article, we will provide a comprehensive guide to debugging in Azure Cloud, including best practices, tools, and code examples. 💻
Before diving into debugging techniques, it is important to understand the different types of issues that can arise in a production environment.</description></item><item><title>Understanding a fair comparison between Cassandra MongoDB and MySQL 👨🏼‍💻</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/cassaandra-mongodb-mysql/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/cassaandra-mongodb-mysql/</guid><description>When choosing between Cassandra, MongoDB, and MySQL, it&amp;rsquo;s important to consider the specific requirements of your project and how each database management system (DBMS) meets those needs.
Here are some points to consider when deciding which DBMS to use:
➜ Data model : Cassandra and MongoDB are both NoSQL databases, which means they use a non-relational data model. This can be beneficial for handling large amounts of unstructured data, or for storing data with complex relationships.</description></item><item><title>Deploying microservices to Azure Kubernetes Service: A tutorial</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/azure-kubernetes-service/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/azure-kubernetes-service/</guid><description>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) is a managed Kubernetes service offered by Microsoft Azure. It enables users to quickly and easily deploy, manage, and scale containerized applications on Azure.
Kubernetes is an open-source container orchestration platform that allows developers to automate the deployment, scaling, and management of containerized applications. It uses a declarative configuration to define the desired state of an application and continuously works to maintain that state.
With AKS, users can leverage the power of Kubernetes without having to worry about the underlying infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Building a scalable and reliable e-commerce platform with .NET and Azure 🫡</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/ecommerce-platform-with-dotnet-and-azure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/ecommerce-platform-with-dotnet-and-azure/</guid><description>E-commerce is an increasingly competitive and fast-paced industry, and building a scalable and reliable e-commerce platform is crucial for success. .NET and Azure offer a powerful combination of technologies for building such a platform, providing the tools you need to create a beautiful and intuitive shopping experience, store and manage product data, process payments, fulfill orders, and optimize performance.
In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to use .NET and Azure to build a scalable and reliable e-commerce platform, covering the following topics:</description></item><item><title>Best practices for securing your Azure Kubernetes Service deployment</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/securing-azure-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/securing-azure-kubernetes/</guid><description>Securing your Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) deployment is crucial to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of your applications and data. In this blog post, we will explore some best practices for securing your AKS deployment.
1. Use Azure AD for authentication and authorization . Azure AD provides centralized identity and access management for your AKS cluster. You can use Azure AD to authenticate users and grant them access to the cluster and its resources.</description></item><item><title>A Beginner's Guide to Multi-Cloud Networking: Key Concepts and Best Practices</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/multicloud-networking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 20:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/multicloud-networking/</guid><description>Multi-cloud networking refers to the ability to connect and use multiple cloud computing environments, such as Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft Azure, and Google Cloud Platform (GCP), in a coordinated manner. This allows organizations to take advantage of the different features and capabilities offered by each cloud provider, and to create a more resilient and flexible infrastructure.
There are several ways to enable multi-cloud networking, depending on your specific requirements and the tools and services you are using.</description></item><item><title>Maximizing Cloud-Native Success with the Twelve-Factor App Methodology 🫡</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/twelve-factor-app/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 17:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/twelve-factor-app/</guid><description>Twelve Factor App Methodology The Twelve-Factor App methodology is a set of best practices for building and deploying cloud-native applications. It was developed by Heroku, a cloud platform as a service (PaaS) provider, and has since been widely adopted by organizations as a guide for building cloud-native applications.
The Twelve-Factor App methodology consists of 12 principles that are designed to help developers build applications that are easy to scale, maintain, and deploy in a cloud environment.</description></item><item><title>Azure Databricks for Enthusiasts: A Beginner's Guide</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/when-and-why-to-use-azure-databricks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 22:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/when-and-why-to-use-azure-databricks/</guid><description>Azure Data Bricks Azure Databricks is a powerful analytics platform that combines the best of Apache Spark and Azure cloud computing. It is a fully managed service that allows users to quickly and easily build, train, and deploy machine learning models, as well as explore and analyze large data sets.
So, when might Azure Databricks be a good choice for your organization? Here are a few key scenarios:
➼ Large-scale data processing and analysis: If you have large data sets that need to be processed and analyzed quickly, Azure Databricks can be a great solution.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Native vs Cloud Agnostic: Weighing the Trade-Offs 🤜 🤛</title><link>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/cloud-native-vs-cloud-agnostic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 20:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://AceTheOps.com/blog/cloud-native-vs-cloud-agnostic/</guid><description>Background Speed ​​is an important factor for business in this era when customers are looking for instant gratification. If the fact doesn&amp;rsquo;t convince you, the statistics might. An element as simple as a website&amp;rsquo;s load time carries weight. Statistics indicate that the first five seconds of a page load time have the greatest impact on conversion rates. So when consumer behavior has the greatest impact, it is profitable in the long run to modernize a business model accordingly.</description></item></channel></rss>