<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cloud-agnostic on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</title><link>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/tags/cloud-agnostic/</link><description>Recent content in cloud-agnostic on Ace The Operations of Corporate World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 17:38:27 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/tags/cloud-agnostic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Maximizing Cloud-Native Success with the Twelve-Factor App Methodology 🫡</title><link>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/twelve-factor-app/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 17:38:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/twelve-factor-app/</guid><description>Twelve Factor App Methodology The Twelve-Factor App methodology is a set of best practices for building and deploying cloud-native applications. It was developed by Heroku, a cloud platform as a service (PaaS) provider, and has since been widely adopted by organizations as a guide for building cloud-native applications.
The Twelve-Factor App methodology consists of 12 principles that are designed to help developers build applications that are easy to scale, maintain, and deploy in a cloud environment.</description></item><item><title>Why Your Organization Needs a Service Mesh: The Benefits of Service Mesh Architecture and Istio</title><link>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/service-mesh-and-istio/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 20:18:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://Preview.AceTheOps.com/blog/service-mesh-and-istio/</guid><description>Background A lot has changed about how we built microservices, and most people have no choice but to deploy microservices as pods in Kubernetes. Let us take an example where we are running a web application that queries data for the products. If both of these functionalities were on the webserver, then a calculation could slow the response time of the web pages. Having it on a seperate server avoids this problem.</description></item></channel></rss>